RG 004:163, Windham Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Windham Probate Court records
1719-1966
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Windham District)
89.75 cubic feet
Record books, 1719-1921; Bond record books, 1881-1966; Probate files, 1719-1925.
RG004_163
1921-040, 2011-013, 2012-009
Historical Note
Windham, Windham County, Town established in May 1692
The Windham Probate District was constituted October 1719, from the Hartford and New London Probate Districts. It also served the following municipalities at various times: Ashford, October 1719 - May 1752; Canterbury, October 1719 - May 1747; Chaplin, May 1822 - June 6, 1850; Columbia, May 1804 - May 1808; Coventry, October 1719 - May 1789; Hampton, October 1786 - June 2, 1836; Killingly, October 1719 - May 1747; Lebanon, October 1719 - June 1, 1826; Mansfield, October 1719 - May 29, 1831; Plainfield, October 1719 - May 1747; Pomfret, October 1719 - May 1752; Scotland, May 1857 - January 4, 2011; Union, October 1734 - May 1752; Voluntown, May 1726 - May 1747; Woodstock, May 1749 - May 1752. The Windham Probate District merged with the Colchester, Eastford (part), and Hampton Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Windham - Colchester Probate District, which serves the municipalities of Chaplin, Colchester, Hampton, Lebanon, Scotland, and Windham.
Town of Windham, Probate District chronology:
May 1692 - October 1719, Hartford County Court and District
May 1692 - October 1719, New London County Court and District
October 1719 - January 4, 2011, Windham District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Windham - Colchester District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books: Regular, vol. 1-38, 1719-1921; Special, vol. 1-12, 1734-1921; Orders & decrees, vol. 13-25, 1881-1921; Bonds, vol. 1-8, 1881-1966; Insolvent estates, vol. 1-3, 1877-1903. Contact the probate court to access original record books numbered after these volumes. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1719-1925. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1729-1917 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2011-013 are by the following and numbered therein: regular, special, orders & decrees, bonds, insolvent estates.
Probate files in accession 1932-040 are arranged alphabetically.
Probate files in accession 2012-009 are arranged by file number.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1921-040 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the files in accession 2012-009.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Ashford; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Canterbury; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Chaplin; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Columbia; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Coventry; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Hampton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Killingly; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Lebanon; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Mansfield; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Plainfield; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Pomfret; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Scotland; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Union; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Voluntown; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Windham; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Woodstock
Places:
Ashford (Conn.); Canterbury (Conn.); Chaplin (Conn.); Columbia (Conn.); Coventry (Conn.); Hampton (Conn.); Killingly (Conn.); Lebanon (Conn.); Mansfield (Conn.); Plainfield (Conn.); Pomfret (Conn.); Scotland (Conn.); Union (Conn.); Voluntown (Conn.); Windham (Conn.); Woodstock (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-013, Record books, 1719-1966, and Accession 2012-019, Probate files, 1880-1961, bulk 1905-1942, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files from 1921-1946 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, vol. 1-34, 1719-1918; Special record books, vol. 1-12, 16, 19-23, 1734-1917; probate files, 1719-1880; and inventory control book were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1921-040 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): July 15, 1921 (1719-1917).
The record books in accession 2011-013 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on August 18, 2010.
The probate files in accession 2012-009 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on October 24, 2011.
Container List
- Record books, 1838-1966; 43.5 cubic feet (82 volumes); 2011-013
  - Regular, 1838-1844 (Volume 1)
  - Regular, 1734-1744 (Volume 2)
  - Regular, 1744-1750 (Volume 3)
  - Regular, 1750-1755 (Volume 4)
  - Regular, 1755-1760 (Volume 5)
  - Regular, 1759-1764 (Volume 6)
  - Regular, 1764-1769 (Volume 7)
  - Regular, 1769-1775 (Volume 8)
  - Regular, 1775-1778 (Volume 9)
  - Regular, 1778-1782 (Volume 10)
  - Regular, 1782-1785 (Volume 11)
  - Regular, 1785-1790 (Volume 12)
  - Regular, 1790-1796 (Volume 13)
  - Regular, 1796-1802 (Volume 14)
  - Regular, 1802-1810 (Volume 15)
  - Regular, 1810-1816 (Volume 16)
  - Regular, 1816-1823 (Volume 17)
  - Regular, 1823-1827 (Volume 18)
  - Regular, 1827-1830 (Volume 19)
  - Regular, 1830-1836 (Volume 20)
  - Regular, 1836-1848 (Volume 21)
  - Regular, 1843-1858 (Volume 22)
  - Regular, 1867-1877 (Volume 23)
  - Regular, 1877-1885 (Volume 24)
  - Regular, 1885-1890 (Volume 25)
  - Regular, 1890-1893 (Volume 26)
  - Regular, 1893-1896 (Volume 27)
  - Regular, 1896-1898 (Volume 28)
  - Regular, 1898-1901 (Volume 29)
  - Regular, 1901-1904 (Volume 30)
  - Regular, 1904-1908 (Volume 31)
  - Regular, 1908-1910 (Volume 32)
  - Regular, 1910-1911 (Volume 33)
  - Regular, 1911-1918 (Volume 34)
  - Regular, 1917-1918 (Volume 35)
  - Regular, 1918-1919 (Volume 36)
  - Regular, 1919-1920 (Volume 37)
  - Special, 1734-1744 (Volume 1)
  - Special, 1744-1755 (Volume 2)
  - Special, 1755-1764 (Volume 3)
  - Special, 1764-1778 (Volume 4)
  - Special, 1778-1797 (Volume 5)
  - Special, 1797-1814 (Volume 6)
  - Special, 1814-1822 (Volume 7)
  - Special, 1822-1829 (Volume 8)
  - Special, 1830-1843 (Volume 9)
  - Special, 1849-1867 (Volume 10)
  - Special, 1869-1873 (Volume 11)
  - Special, 1873-1877 (Volume 12)
  - Special, 1894-1899 (Volume 16)
  - Special, 1899-1904 (Volume 19)
  - Special, 1903-1906 (Volume 20)
  - Special, 1906-1908 (Volume 21)
  - Special, 1908-1913 (Volume 22)
  - Special, 1912-1917 (Volume 23)
  - Special, 1918-1920 (Volume 24)
  - Special, 1920-1921 (Volume 25)
  - Orders & decrees, 1881-1887 (Volume 13)
  - Orders & decrees, 1887-1893 (Volume 14)
  - Orders & decrees, 1887-1895 (Volume 15)
  - Orders & decrees, 1892-1897 (Volume 16)
  - Orders & decrees, 1900-1904 (Volume 17)
  - Orders & decrees, 1900-1904 (Volume 18)
  - Orders & decrees, 1904-1906 (Volume 19)
  - Orders & decrees, 1907-1910 (Volume 20)
  - Orders & decrees, 1910-1916 (Volume 21)
  - Orders & decrees, 1913-1916 (Volume 22)
  - Orders & decrees, 1914-1918 (Volume 23)
  - Orders & decrees, 1917-1923 (Volume 24)
  - Orders & decrees, 1920-1921 (Volume 25)
  - Bonds, 1881-1894 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1894-1905 (Volume 2)
  - Bonds, 1905-1918 (Volume 3)
  - Bonds, 1918-1928 (Volume 4)
  - Bonds, 1928-1940 (Volume 5)
  - Bonds, 1940-1951 (Volume 6)
  - Bonds, 1934-1958 (Volume 7)
  - Bonds, 1958-1966 (Volume 8)
  - Insolvent estates, 1877 (Volume 1)
  - Insolvent estates, 1893 (Volume 2)
  - Insolvent estates, 1896-1903 (Volume 3)
- Probate files, 1719-1917; 36.25 cubic feet; 1921-040
  - A - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 1-105)
  - W.G. & A.R. Morrison Company, 1880-1917 (Drawer 106)
    Receivership bankruptcy file
  - Commitments to insane hospitals, A - Z, 1880-1917 (Drawer 107)
  - Adoptions, A - Z, 1880-1917 (Drawer 108)
  - Commitments and miscellaneous documents, 1880-1917 (Drawer 109)
- Inventory Control Book, 1719-1917; T003073
  Index of the probate files in accession 1921-040
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1880-1961, bulk 1905-1942; 10 cubic feet; 2012-009
  - File numbers 5 - 16 (Box 1)
  - File numbers 16 - 69 (Box 2)
  - File numbers 79 - 160 (Box 3)
  - File numbers 161 - 244 (Box 4)
  - File numbers 255 - 366 (Box 5)
  - File numbers 377 - 434 (Box 6)
  - File numbers 435 - 512 (Box 7)
  - File numbers 513 - 603 (Box 8)
  - File numbers 604 - 685 (Box 9)
  - File numbers 686 - 762 (Box 10)